For anyone who has ever loved...
A Star Is Born is a drama, music, romance film directed by Frank Pierson.
Drunken, has-been rock star John Norman Howard falls in love with unknown
singer Esther Hoffman after seeing her perform at a club.
He lets her sing a few songs at one of his shows and she
becomes the talk of the music industry.
Esther's star begins to rise, while John's continues to fall.
She tries desperately to get John to sober up and focus on
his music, but it may be too late to save him.
Esther Hoffman, played by Barbra Streisand.
John Norman Howard, played by Kris Kristofferson.
Bobbie Ritchie, played by Gary Busey.
Gary Danziger, played by Oliver Clark.
The Oreos, played by Venetta Fields.
The Oreos, played by Clydie King.
A Star Is Born is a 1976 American musical romantic drama film directed by Frank
Pierson, written by Pierson, John Gregory Dunne, and Joan Didion.
It stars Barbra Streisand as an unknown singer and Kris
Kristofferson as an established rock and roll star.
The two fall in love, only to find her career
ascending while his goes into decline.
A Star Is Born premiered at the Mann Village Theater on December
18, 1976, with a wide release by Warner Bros.
the following day.
A huge box office success, grossing $80 million on a $6 million budget in North
America, it emerged as the second highest-grossing of the year.
Reviews praised its performances and musical score, but
criticized the screenplay and runtime.
At the 49th Academy Awards, the film won Best Original
Song for its love theme "Evergreen".
The film is a remake of the 1937 original with Janet Gaynor and Fredric March, notably adapted in 1954 as a musical
starring Judy Garland and James Mason; and subsequently again in 2018 with Lady Gaga and Bradley Cooper.
The film explores themes of rock star, romance, fame.
The tone is emotional.